Guide to the Celeste Bedford Walker Accessions
The Wittliff Collections
Celeste Bedford Walker Accessions
1925-2017, undated
The Wittliff Collections
Walker, Celeste Bedford
UPWC.18012
2.2 Linear Feet
2 boxes 3 folders, 1 poster, and 1 artifact.
Two accessions of Celeste Bedford Walker's playscripts and screenplays including "Distant Voices", "Greenwood: An American Dream Destroyed", "Sassy Mamas", "Bartersville" and "Camp Logan". Also included are promotional items, photographs, correspondence, newspaper articles and reviews.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Celeste Bedford Walker, 2017, 2018
Scope and Contents
Two accessions of Celeste Bedford Walker's playscripts and screenplays including "Distant Voices", "Greenwood: An American Dream Destroyed", "Sassy Mamas", "Bartersville" and "Camp Logan". Also included are promotional items, photographs, correspondence, newspaper articles and reviews.
Biographical Notes
Acclaimed playwright Celeste Bedford Walker is the author of over twenty plays that have received numerous accolades including national awards and productions. She has received the August Wilson Playwriting Award, multiple NAACP Image Awards, New York's AUDELCO Award, and she was a finalist for the Susan Smith Blackburn Prize. The New York Times has praised her plays as "forceful, well-crafted" and "vigorous social satire" and "an uproariously good time." Dramalogue has described her work as "practically flawless." Her play Camp Logan has been performed at major venues around the country, including the Kennedy Center in Washington D.C., where the Washington Post lauded her as "a textbook example of how to simultaneously entertain and educate an audience."
Drama; Screenplays; Dramatists -- Texas; American drama -- African American authors; African American women authors; Walker, Celeste Bedford
- Accession 2018-012, .2 Linear Feet
  Abstract
  Donation by Celeste Bedford Walker of her typescript plays, "Distant Voices", "Sassy Mamas", "Greenwood: An American Dream Destroyed", and "Reunion in Bartersville", included in the collection are synopses, reviews, Walker's Biography, and her induction into the Texas Institute of Letters, 1983-2017.
  - Typescripts of "Distant Voices" and "Greenwood": An American Dream Destroyed" by Walker commissioned by The Ensemble Theatre, including synopsis and reviews, (1 of 3), October 1998 (Box 1673, Folder 14)
  - Typescript of "Sassy Mamas" by Walker, including article "Laughter is the Heart of Loveable 'Sassy Mamas'" by Wei-Huan Chen, (2 of 3), 2007-2016 (Box 1673, Folder 15)
  - Typescript of "Reunion in Bartersville" by Walker, including correspondence, Walker's Bio, list of plays, articles about Walker, and her induction into TIL, (3 of 3), 1987-2017 (Box 1673, Folder 16)
- Accession 2019-039, 2 Linear Feet
  Additions to the Celeste Bedford Walker archival collection from 1925-2012. The majority of the materials included in the collection are promotional flyers, photographs, correspondence, and newspaper articles relating to Walker's play, Camp Logan and other plays such as Once in a Wife Time. Also included in the collection are two The New York Times papers from 1925-1926.
  - Note from Walker indicating the materials donated, undated (Box 2958, Folder 1)
  - Camp Logan stage play with penciled change to Sgt. McKinney's age from 35 to 40, undated (Box 2958, Folder 2)
  - Camp Logan: A World War I screenplay, first draft, adapted from the stage play, Camp Logan, September, 1998 (Box 2958, Folder 3)
  - Camp Logan scene breakdown with handwritten annotations, followed by 2 handwritten pages, undated (Box 2958, Folder 4)
  - Mountaintop Productions, Mountain Special Series, History as Drama Workshop, "Act n' Write" with Walker's bio, Alley Theatre Hype Workshop "Once in a Wife Time" partial script, Camp Logan partial script, program for Mountaintop Productions/Montgomery County Community College Camp Logan, January 16, 1993 (Box 2958, Folder 5)
  - Envelope with photos and correspondence relating to Camp Logan, circa 1918-1986 (Box 2958, Folder 6)
  - Camp Logan clippings, including clippings about the performance at Texas Festival at the Kennedy Center, 1990-1995 (Box 2958, Folder 7)
  - DVD "Buffalo Soldier Mutiny Houston 1917" and a "Camp Logan Sound [Effects, Cues]", 2008 (Box 2958, Folder 8)
  - Two cassettes titled "The Regal Theatre: 60 Camp Logan WLNR/WJPC" and "Camp Logan commercial", undated (Box 2958, Folder 9)
  - Camp Logan announcements, clippings, and correspondence, 1990-1997 (Box 2958, Folder 10)
  - Camp Logan photocopies of clippings, announcements for Los Angeles show at Robey Theatre, 1989-1991 (Box 2958, Folder 11)
  - Camp Logan research, reviews, and script fragments, 1989-2005 (Box 2958, Folder 12)
  - The Houston Riot and Courts-Martial of 1917 booklets, The Buffalo Soldiers, America's Black Regiments of the West pamphlets, and Camp Logan programs, 1998 (Box 2958, Folder 13)
  - Camp Logan flyers and announcements, 1989-2005 (Box 2958, Folder 14)
  - Letters, flyers, prize information, clippings, and PR materials for Camp Logan and Walker's other plays, 1994-2011 (Box 2958, Folder 15)
  - Photos, flyers, reviews, and clippings for Camp Logan, Once in a Wife Time, and other Walker plays, including 2 "The Barbara Jordan Story Promo Teaser" DVDs, 1986-2007 (Box 2958, Folder 16)
  - Bluebonnet Award for Achievement to Celeste Bedford Walker, 1995 (Box 2958, Folder 17)
  - Two color photos from Camp Logan, one of which is on mounted sheet, undated (Box 2959, Folder 1)
  - "The War Within" article on Camp Logan, February 15, 1996 (Box 2959, Folder 2)
  - Three Camp Logan-Mountaintop Production photos, undated (Box 2959, Folder 3)
  - The New York Times Book Review section, condition is brittle and crumbling, August 22, 1926 (Box 2959, Folder 4)
  - The New York Times magazine section, condition is brittle and crumbling, November 22, 1925 (Box 2959, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Item: Camp Logan 44"x 32" poster, May 27, 2012 (Map-case Dr. 7)
  - Mounted soldier figure, 13.5" tall, attached plaque reads "To Camp Logan from XVIII ABN Corp EO Office", this is 18th Airborne Corps, stationed at Fort Bragg, undated (Box 3532, Item 1)